Guide to the Arthur Sperry Pearse papers, 1904-1960 UA.29.02.0012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic Material, 1911-1953; 6 boxes
  - Photographic prints, 1912-1953; 1 boxes; Approximately 367 prints
    - People, circa 1915, circa 1930, 1953 (Box 7)
      Pearse's wife, Mary Lehmer Pearse; colleagues David and Nelle Causey (biologist and zoologist, respectively); and a signed portrait mounted on cardstock frame, circa 1915, of T.R.R. (Thomas Roscoe Rede) Stebbing (1835-1926), naturalist and supporter of Darwinism.
    - Port Aransas, University of Texas Institute of Marine Science, undated (Box 7)
    - Siam, 1929-1930 (Box 7)
    - Tortugas, 1931 (Box 7)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 7)
      Most of these loose images are from the same locations as other identified prints.
    - Venezuela, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Yucatán, 1934, 1936 (Box 7)
    - Yucatán (caves), 1934, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Glass-plate lantern slides, circa 1911-1936, 4 boxes
    Contains positive glass lantern slides in 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 and 4x5 inch formats, used by Pearse in lectures and presentations. Subjects are the same as the photographic prints and negatives. Also present are teaching slides used by Arthur Pearse in course lectures, which are primarily copies of maps, graphs and charts, illustrations, and photos taken from other published works. Slides are housed in archival boxes within boxes 8-11.
    Glass slides are extremely vulnerable and are restricted. Please consider using similar images in other formats. Access copies can also be made on advance request.
    Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
    - 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 Slides (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8a)
      - Crabs, undated (Box 8a)
      - Oysters, undated (Box 8a)
      - Unidentified locations, undated (Box 8a)
      - Teaching slides, undated (Box 8a)
      - Teaching slides, undated (Box 8b)
    - 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 Slides (Box 9)
      - Teaching slides, undated (Box 9a)
      - Panama, undated (Box 9a)
      - Japan, circa 1930 (Box 9b)
      - Yucatan, 1934-1936 (Box 9b)
      - India, 1929 (Box 9b)
      - St. Louis, MO, 1911-1912 (Box 9b)
      - Madison, WI, undated (Box 9b)
      - Bahama Islands, undated (Box 9b)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9b)
    - 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 Slides (Box 10)
      - Colombia, 1913 (Box 10a)
      - Africa, 1926 (Box 10a)
      - Africa, 1926 (Box 10b)
      - Massachusetts, 1912-1913 (Box 10b)
      - Philippine Islands, Manila, circa 1929 (Box 10b)
      - Philippine Islands, circa 1929 (Box 10b)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10b)
    - 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 and 4 x 5 Slides (Box 11)
      - Siam, 1929-1930 (Box 11a)
      - Sturgeon Bay, WI, 1920 (Box 11a)
      - Tortugas, 1931 (Box 11a)
      - Columbia, 1913 (Box 11a)
      - Japan, 1929-1930 (Box 11b)
      - Teaching slides, undated (Box 11b)
  - Safety and nitrate negatives, circa 1913-1938; 4 boxes Approximately 1255 negatives
    All negatives are closed to use. Access copies are available in the form of photographic prints or digital scan. As these require advance preparation, please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this collection.
    About half of these sheet negatives have captions written on their edges. There are roughly double the number of negatives as there are prints, thus in this subseries there are many images not found in paper print format. The most typical sizes are 2 1/4 x 3 1/4 and 4 x 5 inches. Most are on nitrate film.
    As with the prints, the largest series are from Nigeria and the Yucatán, with about 200 images each; there are also substantial groups from Beaufort, North Carolina, Alabama, Florida, Colombia, China, Japan, the Philippines, India, Thailand, the Tortugas, and Venezuela. Many of these images are not found among the prints.
    - Africa (Nigeria), 1926; 189 items (Box 12)
    - Alabama, 1925 (Box 12)
    - Albatross Reefs [Australia?], 1929-1930? (Box 12)
    - Assorted: Lerner Marine Lab [Bimini, Bahamas]; passengers on the S.S. Metapan (1913); sand dunes, Millers, Indiana; Salisbury Cave [Connecticut?], 1913 and undated (Box 12)
      Includes an original envelope marked "Deck passengers on S.S. Metapan, June 29, 1913."
    - Beaufort, NC, 1936-1938 (Box 12)
    - Burma, 1929-1930 (Box 12)
    - China, 1930 (Box 12)
    - Colombia, 1913 (Box 12)
    - Duke Forest, 1934 (Box 13)
    - England, 1926 (Box 13)
    - Florida, undated (Box 13)
    - India, 1929-1930 (Box 13)
    - Japan, 1929-1930 (Box 13)
    - Maine, undated (Box 13)
    - Maps, charts, and illustrations for publications (Nitrate), 1920s-1930s?; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Maps, charts, and illustrations for publications (Safety), 1930s?; 63 items (Box 14)
    - Massachusetts, 1912-1913 (Box 14)
    - Passport pictures (Pearse), circa 1930s (Box 14)
    - Philippine Islands, undated (Box 14)
    - Port Aransas, University of Texas Institute of Marine Science, undated (Box 14)
    - Siam [Thailand], 1929-1930 (Box 14)
    - Sturgeon Bay, Wisconsin, 1920 (Box 15)
    - Tortugas, 1931 (Box 15)
    - Unidentified images, undated (Nitrate) (Box 15)
    - Venezuela, 1918 (Box 15)
    - Yucatán, 1934, 1936 (Box 15)
    - Yucatán (caves) (Box 15)